MARK SKINNER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



james-m-skinner
github.com/jmskinne

jmskinne@gmail.com

<u>www.markskinner.co</u>

PROFILE

Prior to my work as a software developer, I was a public librarian serving mainly in public-facing and managerial roles. Working in that sector gave me valuable experience in problem-solving, team building, and goal-oriented work, whether individually or within a group. These lessons, combined with my lifelong love of technology and computing, have allowed me to combine my curiosity, problem-solving skills, and ability to work within a team in order to make tangible improvements to applications and websites. I am excited to begin this new career and see where the many opportunities in software development take me.

EDUCATION

Nashville Software School Full-Stack Software Developer

Wayne State University
Master of Library and Information
Science

University of Alabama at Birmingham Master of Arts in History

PROJECTS

Queue - React, Django

Queue serves as way for users to plan their vacation to Disney World. They can view wait times for rides, plan their daily itinerary, use Google Maps for walking directions between rides, view historical wait times, and chat with other users about their upcoming trip. Queue was built using React, Django, Google Maps API, Reactstrap, and ThemeParksAPI.

https://github.com/jmskinne/queued-server

BookClub - React

BookClub allows readers to connect through messages boards to discuss the books they are reading and keep of a library of their current and past books. BookClub was built using React, Google Books API, and Reactstrap.

https://github.com/jmskinne/bookclub

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

Nashville Software School | 2020-2021

Full time 6-month software development program learning full stack technologies

- Built one page applications using React, Python, HTML5, CSS, Javascript, Git, Github, APIs, and SQL
- Participated in daily standups and worked remotely using Zoom
- Created CRUD applications in group and individual projects
- Developed data structures for projects using entity relationship diagrams

Group Projects:

Rare - React, Django

- Tools used: React, Django, Python, SQL, and Github
- Single page application designed for users to share, comment, and react to different articles
- Implemented with full CRUD functionality and user/administrator views
- Individually responsible for CRUD functionally of the comment, reaction, and user profile components

MARK SKINNER

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER



jmskinne@gmail.com
205-718-0330
james-m-skinner
github.com/jmskinne
www.markskinner.co

Group Projects Continued: Nutshell - Javascript

- Tools used: Javascript, HTML, CSS, and Github
- Single page application designed to organize a user's news, tasks, and events
- Implemented with full CRUD functionality
- Individually responsible for CRUD functionally of the tasks component and implementing weather information from the Weatherbit.io API

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

LIBRARY MANAGER

Birmingham Public Llbrary | 2010-2020

- Empowered and trained 15 staff members to provide excellent, patron-centered service for the library branch
- Created and implemented special programs for youth, teens, and adults primarily focusing on STEAM learning
- Fostered relationships and performed community engagement with neighborhood associations, civic groups, businesses, and schools
- Served as vice-moderator for circulation roundtable and participated in various committees such as local authors, technology, strategic planning, website improvement, security review, and youth services
- Maintained branch collection using circulation statistics in Sierra to inform deselection and consulted a variety of resources when selecting new items for purchase

LIBRARIAN

Birmingham Holocaust Education Center | 2015 - 2018

- Oversaw the re-opening of the library by growing the collection from 400 to 5000 items
- Catalogued all items and successfully transitioned from paper records to a budget-appropriate ILS
- Used MarcEdit and Z39.50 protocols to create and update records
- · Performed outreach to local universities and managed library interns and volunteers
- · Wrote library polices and assisted the executive director with the grant process